A Guide to the Hampton D. Smith Collection, 1974-1990
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Hampton D. Smith Collection, 1974-1990
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms2012-079
3.0 cu. ft. 2 boxes; 2 oversized folders
The Hampton D. Smith Collection, consists of a collection of papers, raw data, presentations, and laboratory notes pertaining to Dr. Hampton D. Smith's work in the Virginia Tech Chemistry Department from 1974 to 1990.
Smith, Hampton D.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The Hampton D. Smith Collection was acquired by Special Collections in 2007.
Scope and Content
The Hampton D. Smith Collection collection contains research and lab tests pertaining to the formation of undiscovered carboranes and nitriles created by Smith and other collaborators. The collection contains raw data spanning a period of over fifteen years (1974-1990), and several formal proposals pertaining to theories developed from that data. The correspondence is primarily between Smith and chemists at other prominent universities and colleges, and discuss the possible theories regarding the synthesis and formation of carboranes.
Arrangement
The collection is organized by type (research data, charts, notebooks). Within each type, files are organized alphabetically by folder title. Original folder titles were retained whenever possible.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Chemistry; Faculty; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Occupations:
Chemists
Contents List
- ACiO + CaCO3 Unknowns (Box-folder 1-1)
- Article Reprints (3 folders) (Box-folder 1-2 to 1-4)
- Alfred P. Sloan Foundation (Box-folder 1-5)
- American Chemical Society Meeting, 12 March 1978, Anaheim CA (Box-folder 1-6)
- American Chemical Society Paper, 3 August 1976, San Francisco, CA (Box-folder 1-7)
- Boron Nitrate- Review Paper (Box-folder 1-8)
- Boron Papers (Box-folder 1-9)
- BX3/Nitriles (Box-folder 1-10)
- Carboranes: Article Reprints and Notes (Box-folder 1-11)
- Carborane Papers (Box-folder 1-12)
- Correspondence, University of South Carolina (Box-folder 1-13)
- Five Coordinate Nikel Complexrde of 12, Bi5(dyphenylphosphine) (Box-folder 1-14)
- Galbraith Laboratories- Analyses (Box-folder 1-15)
- Hydrogen Storage- Carboranes (Box-folder 1-16)
- Infrared Data- Arsenic Carborane (Box-folder 1-17)
- Inorganic Synthesis (Box-folder 1-18)
- Investigation of the HCl-NO2-CO-Ni2t System, A Possible Catalytic Rout for the Conversion of HCl to COCl2 (Box-folder 1-19)
- Mass Spectrometer Data (Box-folder 1-20)
- National Science Foundation (Box-folder 1-21)
- Polymers Derived from 1, 2 -BI5 (Mercapto), Carboranes and Isocyantes (Box-folder 1-22)
- Proposal Data (2 folders), 1979 (Box-folder 1-23 to 1-24)
- Proposal Data, Carboranes (2 folders) (Box-folder 1-25 to 1-26)
- Proposal Data- National Science Foundation, 1981 (Box-folder 1-27)
- Proposal: "A Study of Carbon-Based Ligan Transition Metal Complexes" (Box-folder 1-28)
- Proposal Data, 1978 (Box-folder 1-29)
- Proposal Data, 1973 (Box-folder 1-30)
- Proposal Data- VPI, 1973 (Box-folder 1-31)
- Proposal Copies- National Science Foundation, 1980 (Box-folder 1-32)
- Proposal- 8 January, 1978 (Box-folder 1-33)
- Research Data (3 folders) (Box-folder 1-34 to 1-36)
- Research, 1974 (Box-folder 1-37)
- Research Notes, 1974 (Box-folder 1-38)
- Research, 1975 (Box-folder 1-39)
- Research, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 1-40)
- Research, 1979 (Box-folder 1-41)
- Research Data, 1980 (Box-folder 1-42)
- Research Data, 1982 (Box-folder 1-43)
- Research, 1983 (Box-folder 1-44)
- Syntheses and Crystallographic Characterization of Heterocarbons (Box-folder 1-45)
- Synthesis, Characterization, and Selected Reactions of (Ni(CH3CN6)6)(BCl4)2 (Box-folder 1-46)
- Thallium Paper (Box-folder 1-47)
- VPI and S.U. Chemistry Departments (2 folders) (Box-folder 2-1 to 2-2)
- 1, 2, Bi5 (Marcapto)-o-carbonate (Box-folder 2-3)
- 5 Coordinate Research, 1977 (Box-folder 2-4)
- (Cl3 PO BCl) Data, 1976 (Box-folder 2-5)
- IR Spectrum Charts, 1964 (Box-folder 2-6)
- IR Spectrum Charts (2 folders), 1965 (Box-folder 2-7 to 2-8)
- IR Spectra Data (2 folders) (Folder 1 and 2)
- NMR Spectra, 1983 (Box-folder 2-9)
- The Synthesis and Reactions of 1,2,(2-substituted-1,3,2) (Box-folder 2-10)
- The Synthesis and Chemistry of Same Monocarbon and Dicarbon Metallcarboranes (Box-folder 2-11)
- Laboratory Research Notebook, Glenn F. Hermann, Hampton D. Smith (Box-folder 2-12)
- Laboratory Research Notebook, Dr. John Petty (Box-folder 2-13)
- Laboratory Research Notebook, Boron Chemistry, 1982 (Box-folder 2-14)
- Laboratory Research Notebook, Research III, Dr. John Petty (Box-folder 2-15)
- Laboratory Notebook, Boron Research I, Dr. John Petty (Box-folder 2-16)
- Research Notebook, H.D. Smith (2 folders) (Box-folder 2-17 to 2-18)